Paul Rhymer Radio Scripts
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Paul Rhymer Radio Scripts 1934-1944
MSS48652
Rhymer, Paul
1,000 items
14 containers
5.6 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Scriptwriter and humorist. Scripts of the daytime radio series Vic and Sade written by Rhymer for airing on the National Broadcasting Company.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Rhymer, Paul.
Organizations
National Broadcasting Company.
Subjects
Radio comedies.; Radio scripts.
Titles
Paul Rhymer papers; Vic and Sade (Radio program)
Occupations
Authors.; Humorists.
Provenance
The radio scripts of Paul Rhymer, scriptwriter and humorist, were transferred to the Manuscript Division from the Library of Congress Copyright Office in 1972-1973.
Access and Restrictions
Restrictions apply governing the use, photoduplication, or publication of items in this collection. Consult reference staff in the Manuscript Division for information concerning these restrictions. In addition, many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1905 Born, Fulton, Ill.
circa 1925 Attended Illinois Wesleyan University, Bloomington, Ill.
1929 Moved to Chicago, Ill., and began work in continuity department at the National Broadcasting Co.
1931 1945 Writer of Vic and Sade daytime radio series on the National Broadcasting Co.
1933 Married Mary Frances Murray
1936 Vic and Sade voted the best-written program on radio
1938 Voted best scriptwriter by radio artists
1952 Scripted The Public Life of Cliff Norton series, a comedy show for NBC-TV
1964, Oct. 26 Died, Chicago, Ill.
Scope and Content Note
The radio scripts of Paul Rhymer (1905-1964) span the years 1934-1944 and consist of playscripts of Vic and Sade submitted to the Library of Congress for copyright deposit during that period. The Vic and Sade radio series, sponsored by Proctor and Gamble, aired as a daytime comedy on the National Broadcasting Company from November 1934 to December 1945 and won many awards, including for best written program on the radio in 1936.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged according to year or span of years of submission and therein by copyright registration number.
Container List
- Vic and Sade (Box 1)
  - 1934-1935 (Box 1)
    - DU32521, (4 folders) (Box 1)
    - DU32874, (4 folders) (Box 1)
    - DU33854, (5 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1935 (Box 2)
    - DU34194, (4 folders) (Box 2)
    - DU34717, (4 folders) (Box 2)
    - DU35211, (5 folders) (Box 2)
    - DU35730, (5 folders) (Box 3)
    - DU36224, (4 folders) (Box 3)
    - DU36796, (5 folders) (Box 3)
    - DU37273, (5 folders) (Box 4)
    - DU37693, (4 folders) (Box 4)
    - DU38267, (5 folders) (Box 4)
  - 1935-1936 (Box 5)
    - DU38622, (4 folders) (Box 5)
    - DU40025, (5 folders) (Box 5)
    - DU40765, (5 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1936 (Box 6)
    - DU40765 (Box 6)
    - DU41314, (4 folders) (Box 6)
    - DU41828, (5 folders) (Box 6)
    - DU42399, (5 folders) (Box 6)
    - DU42990, (4 folders) (Box 7)
    - DU43621, (5 folders) (Box 7)
    - DU44015, (5 folders) (Box 7)
    - DU44532, (4 folders) (Box 8)
    - DU45096, (5 folders) (Box 8)
    - DU45740, (5 folders) (Box 8)
  - 1936-1937 (Box 9)
    - DU46376, (5 folders) (Box 9)
    - DU46931, (4 folders) (Box 9)
    - DU47654, (6 folders) (Box 9)
  - 1937 (Box 10)
    - DU48296, (3 folders) (Box 10)
    - DU48798, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - DU49568, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - DU50186, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - DU51119, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - DU51149, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - DU51935, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - 1937-1938 (Box 12)
    - DU52411, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - DU52982, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - DU53669, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - DU54292 (Box 12)
  - 1938 (Box 13)
    - Folder 1 (Box 13)
      - DU54292 (Box 13)
      - DU55042 (Box 13)
    - Folder 2 (Box 13)
      - DU55042 (Box 13)
      - DU55609 (Box 13)
    - Folder 3 (Box 13)
      - DU55609 (Box 13)
    - Folder 4 (Box 13)
      - DU55609 (Box 13)
      - DU56145 (Box 13)
      - DU56146 (Box 13)
    - Folder 5 (Box 13)
      - DU56416 (Box 13)
    - Folder 6 (Box 13)
      - DU56416 (Box 13)
      - DU56775 (Box 13)
    - Folder 7 (Box 13)
      - DU56775 (Box 13)
      - DU57987 (Box 13)
      - DU57956 (Box 13)
      - DU58296 (Box 13)
      - DU58830 (Box 13)
      - DU59452 (Box 13)
  - 1938-1944 (Box 14)
    - Folder 1 (Box 14)
      - DU59956 (Box 14)
      - DU60493 (Box 14)
      - DU61022 (Box 14)
      - DU61713 (Box 14)
      - DU62302 (Box 14)
      - DU63542 (Box 14)
      - DU63535 (Box 14)
      - DU63921 (Box 14)
      - DU64388 (Box 14)
      - DU65218 (Box 14)
      - DU65716 (Box 14)
      - DU66270 (Box 14)
      - DU66779 (Box 14)
    - Folder 2 (Box 14)
      - DU67361 (Box 14)
      - DU67766 (Box 14)
      - DU68343 (Box 14)
      - DU68789 (Box 14)
      - DU69341 (Box 14)
      - DU69838 (Box 14)
      - DU70340 (Box 14)
      - DU70680 (Box 14)
      - DU71143 (Box 14)
      - DU71411 (Box 14)
      - DU71954 (Box 14)
      - DU72523 (Box 14)
      - DU72571 (Box 14)
      - DU73241 (Box 14)
    - Folder 3 (Box 14)
      - DU73453 (Box 14)
      - DU73927 (Box 14)
      - DU74344 (Box 14)
      - DU74826 (Box 14)
      - DU75327 (Box 14)
      - DU75545 (Box 14)
      - DU75853 (Box 14)
      - DU77223 (Box 14)
      - DU77735 (Box 14)
      - DU78129 (Box 14)
      - DU78529 (Box 14)
      - DU78766 (Box 14)
    - Folder 4 (Box 14)
      - DU79104 (Box 14)
      - DU79458 (Box 14)
      - DU79799 (Box 14)
      - DU80126 (Box 14)
      - DU80437 (Box 14)
      - DU81395 (Box 14)
      - DU81468 (Box 14)
      - DU81925 (Box 14)
      - DU82110 (Box 14)
      - DU82392 (Box 14)
      - DU82601 (Box 14)
      - DU83021 (Box 14)
    - Folder 5 (Box 14)
      - DU83187 (Box 14)
      - DU83572 (Box 14)
      - DU83856 (Box 14)
      - DU84379 (Box 14)
      - DU84510 (Box 14)
      - DU84803 (Box 14)
      - DU84997 (Box 14)
      - DU85256 (Box 14)
      - DU85719 (Box 14)
      - DU85939 (Box 14)
      - DU86324 (Box 14)
      - DU86567 (Box 14)
    - Folder 6 (Box 14)
      - DU86888 (Box 14)
      - DU87142 (Box 14)
      - DU88409 (Box 14)
      - DU88758 (Box 14)
      - DU89226 (Box 14)
      - DU89701 (Box 14)
      - DU89976 (Box 14)
      - DU90450 (Box 14)
      - DU90746 (Box 14)